<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3D Printing on Tarek</title>
    <link>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/categories/3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3D Printing on Tarek</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/categories/3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AUTONMOUS 3D PRINTED UAV</title>
      <link>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2024/05/01/autonmous-3d-printed-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2024/05/01/autonmous-3d-printed-uav/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview: 3D-Printed UAVs with Coordinated Flight Capabilities Step 1. Understand the Objective UAE University students developed two 3D-printed UAVs capable of coordinated figure-eight flight at altitudes up to 450 meters. The project utilized a Creality 3D printer to achieve precise and cost-effective production, showcasing an innovative approach to UAV design and manufacturing.&#xA;Step 2. Learn the Key Details As shown in this video, the UAVs are equipped with advanced tracking algorithms to enable synchronized flight, making them ideal for applications such as environmental monitoring and surveillance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DRONE EQUIED ROBOTIC ARM</title>
      <link>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2024/05/01/drone-equied-robotic-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2024/05/01/drone-equied-robotic-arm/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview: &amp;ldquo;Sure Plus&amp;rdquo; Project - 3D Printed Drone with Autonomous Capabilities Step 1. Understand the Objective The &amp;ldquo;Sure Plus&amp;rdquo; project from UAE University is a six-month program focused on developing a unique drone 3D printed in one piece to enhance strength and simplify the design. The drone is equipped with a robotic arm to perform autonomous tasks, demonstrating its ability to execute missions independently.&#xA;Step 2. Learn the Key Details This innovative technology, showcased in this video, represents a significant advancement in drone capabilities and applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AUTONMOUS DRONE-ROVER</title>
      <link>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2023/05/01/autonmous-drone-rover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tarekdief.github.io/TarekD_Portfolio/blog/2023/05/01/autonmous-drone-rover/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview: Drone and Rover Integration for Enhanced Mobility and Versatility Step 1. Understand the Objective The project focuses on integrating a drone and a rover to overcome challenges related to yaw motion and stability issues caused by incorrect sensor readings. This integration enhances mobility across varied terrains and offers versatility for both aerial and ground operations.&#xA;Step 2. Learn the Key Details As showcased in this video, the combined drone and rover system provides significant benefits, including the ability to adapt to different scenarios and environments.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
